Mykhailo Poda

J +421 952-061-544

mykhail.poda@gmail.com
in linkedin.com/in/mykhail-poda

in linkedin.com/in/mykhail-poda

Education

NTUU "I. Sikorsky KPI"

2015 - 2017

Master of Science in Electrical Machines and Apparatus

Kyiv, Ukraine

Summary

System Engineer with over 5+ years of experience with deep knowledge in a base stack of 3 major clouds (like AWS, GCP, Azure), hands-on CI/CD practices, orchestration, automation tools, and programming languages. Successfully released 3 projects to production. Lead a team of up to 4 people.

Technical Skills

Languages: Python, Bash, Java, JavaScript, SQL

Technologies: Docker (5+ years), K8s (3,5+ years), AWS (5+ years), GCP (3+ years), Azure (2+ years), Jenkins(5+ years), GitHub CI, Ansible, Terraform, Packer, PostgreSQL, MongoDB, Redis, RabbitMQ, Nginx

Experience

EPAM Systems, LLC

September 2020 - November 2023

Lead System Engineer

Kyiv, Ukraine

- Led the design and implementation of architectural solutions that streamlined the deployment process for new services, leading to a 20% decrease in time required to launch products, resulting in increased customer satisfaction and a 7% boost in revenue growth.
- Rewamp infrastructure as a code by replacing Bash, Python, and Powershell scripts with Ansible. Greatly reduced the number of it up to 90%. Documented all previously used in Ansible pipelines.
- Automated internal onboarding processes by developing and implementing a streamlined system for creating accounts, issuing permissions, and connecting application packages. Resulting in a 25% reduction in onboarding time and increased overall team efficiency.
- Reducing the load on the monitoring support department by 40% by creating a slack bot.
- Managed a team of 2 to 4 people with more than 90% utilization of available resources.

L-Soft, LLC

May 2019 - August 2020

DevOps Engineer

Kyiv, Ukraine

- Unifying Terraform configurations in multi-cloud infrastructure (AWS, GCP, Azure) with a single variables entry point. In conclusion, it gave rise to speed implementation of new services by 13% in production.
- Speeded up server provisioning by 20% by introducing Ansible and transferring bash scripts to its basis. This also boosts the readability and maintainability of the code.
- The rethought approach of rolling up new deployments, in fact, reduced the speed of foremost for new environments by 15% by introducing complex programmable Jenkins pipelines.

Ukrposhta, Inc

August 2018 – April 2019

DevOps Engineer

Kyiv, Ukraine

- Improved release stability and frequency by 20% by implementing the GitLab pipeline for automated tests and deploying API for different environments.
- \bullet Rethink approaches to company deployments in general and raise service stability from 80% to over 95% by implementing blue-green deployment.
- Designed and maintained social network bots for support over 5M customers on Facebook, Viber, and Telegram, which helps get company services on the go without developing mobile/web applications at no cost.
- Led the maintenance of 8 database clusters and 20 server nodes with more than 20M operations/day with on-time delivery for prod and nonprod environments.